Was it Your Grace who sent
Scarlett to the scaffold?
What makes you think so?
The conclusive evidence
in Cecilia's attempted assassination
was the bottle of poison
found in Scarlett's chambers.
Someone snuck through a duke's house
and planted that in his daughter's room.
Only one person could do that
without leaving a trace,
and that person is you.
You arranged Scarlett's execution.
Strangely, he and I came
into the world on the same day.
Yes, I'm so capable that
I surprise even myself,
but I still wish to serve you.
So take pride, Ern.
Dolphy, you can't be serious.
Remarry? Me?
The Republic of Soldita is begging me
to take a descendant
of Cornelia Faris off their hands.
I can't trust a lineage that dangerous
to just any noble house.
So, well, you're my only real option.
Honestly... The things I do for you.
I am Aliénore Shibola.
My bride from across the sea
was the very picture of a good wife.
Her singular shortcoming
was her frail constitution.
However, it wasn't long
before we had Scarlett.
I couldn't help it.
It was out of my hands, I tell you!
Coochie coochie coo.
What a beauty you are!
And you don't cry at the sight of me!
Dylan, don't hold her too long.
What if your stupidity rubs off on her?
Hey!
Did you hear that, sire?!
Wasn't that uncalled for?!
Yes, I heard it, and I share his concern.
You'd better hand
dear little Scarlett back to me.
What do I do? I'm surrounded by enemies!
Looking back, those might
have been the final days
we'd laugh together in blissful ignorance.
Word has it a strange hallucinogen
has been circulating recently.
A drug?!
It's chiefly popular
among young aristocrats,
which makes me wonder
how they're getting it.
Only prominent nobles have the stuff.
And what is this hallucinogen called?
Jackal's Paradise.
At the time, it seemed a trivial matter.
But one day, some months later...
Dylan's been jailed for treason?!
Yes. Given the circumstances,
I doubt he can avoid the headsman.
That's preposterous!
Naturally, Dylan would never turn traitor.
Someone framed him.
And their goal is...
You don't mean... war?
It's Faris. They've secretly
been pulling the strings.
"The Holy Grail of Eris"?
Dylan is a pillar of our border defense.
They'll invade once he's dead.
Then Dylan was sentenced
to death so quickly because...
Yes. We have rats in our midst.
Could Daeg Gallus be using
the drug to secure funds?
Given its popularity
with the upper nobility,
they almost certainly mean
to erode our nation from within.
And amid it all,
one man has seen a meteoric rise.
Simon Darkian!
Question him at once!
He'd only plead ignorance.
We have no proof.
What a disaster!
Is the poisoning accusation against
Scarlett part of their plan as well?
No, that must be coincidence.
They have no motive to harm Scarlett.
That's true...
They want her on the throne.
That means without Scarlett,
their plan falls apart.
In which case...
What am I thinking?!
Sire, I suggest we make use of Scarlett.
Their plan requires a pawn possessing
the blood of the old imperial family.
Executing Scarlett will buy us a way out.
It will stall them and sow the sentiment
that public executions are barbaric.
I'll task Kimberly Smith of the Violet
Association with leading the outcry.
That will allow us
to delay Dylan's execution.
Wait, wait, wait.
In the meantime, I will gather
proof of his innocence.
Wait, Dolphy!
Your Majesty!
Commit the face of every person
who pleads for Scarlett's life to memory.
Their agents will be among them.
We'll show them all
that we shall be the ones
who will have the last laugh.
Supposing that I did engineer
my daughter's execution,
what is that to you?
I'm doing this for her.
"Her"?
May I have your permission to speak?
Yes, of course.
How are you feeling?
If I didn't know any better,
I'd think you were worried about me.
Of course I am. You're my wife.
Listen, dear...
Don't give me that nonsense.
A woman you don't sleep with and only
see to exchange the occasional greeting
isn't what most people would call a wife.
You're thinking of a mere acquaintance.
Are you angry?
I'm only asking that you spare me
your foolery, you dunderhead.
What do you mean?
Why, you can hardly expect
a young lady to spell it out.
I may be a silly little girl,
yet even I know the blood
in my veins could spark a fire.
But do you expect me
to just grin and bear it?
To just accept a life of
being treated like a prisoner?
What is that but a living death?
I think I'd like to be very selfish
and have some harsh words with you.
What?
I believe that when most people say
"harsh words," they do mean words.
Oh, do forgive me.
Back where I come from,
we talk to dunderheads with our fists.
What a lawless place that must be.
I've done a lot of thinking
since I came to this country,
and I've decided to live my life
as I please after all.
That was our dear Cornelia's dying wish.
It was?
Yes. And so...
If you have a complaint,
tell it to Cornelia Faris.
I...
I actually went and did it!
Oh, do forgive me.
But my mother taught me to speak
to dunderheads with my fists.
Th-That was, um, a custom from
the homeland of my friend's mother!
Your friend...?
Y-Yes, something about the best way
to deal with dunderheads.
Oh, not that I mean to call
Your Grace a dunderhead.
What's a little slap?
It hurt a lot worse back then.
So, what else does your friend want?
Shall I offer my head, perhaps?
P-P-Perish the thought!
Is that so?
If you ever have need of it,
you need only ask.
Does Your Grace...
wish to die?
Oh, that must be it.
I've been longing for death, have I?
I deserve to be punished. Otherwise...
She'd be too pitiful for words, robbed
of her life through no fault of her own.
Connie.
If I may...
I have never once thought myself pitiful.
Yes, I felt anger and sadness as well.
But I know how awkward
and proud you are, Father.
You couldn't help yourself.
And you've no reason to pity me.
After all, I know...
that I came into this world loved.
Even I know that you loved me, Father.
There's plenty I'd like to say to you,
but as for the rest of my complaints,
I suppose I'll just have to
tell them to Cornelia Faris.
I see.
You must know what that means.
Oh, I know. I know, all right.
Mother was always saying it.
Scarlett...
I'll have your casket made of jet.
It's a sacred wood, said to guide souls
to the promised land.
And I won't forget a blanket
woven of moonworm cocoons.
I can't have you getting a chill.
Remember how often you caught colds
when you were little?
You grew feverish so quickly,
I couldn't take my eyes off you.
I know. Why don't I add
lovely engravings to your casket?
You never would settle
for less than the best.
Really, you were always so willful and...
Had there been any other way,
I would've given anything for it!
I would have given my own life
many times over!
If only I'd told you even once
that I loved you!
Please, do your best for her.
Simon Darkian is with Daeg Gallus?
Cecilia recently purchased
the Saint Nicholas Hospital.
When Campbell owned it, tax inspectors
gave even blank books a pass.
You don't mean Simon Darkian was
in charge of those inspections, do you?
I mean just that.
A man named Edmond Park,
who did the hospital's accounting,
was found murdered.
To silence him, most likely.
Meaning they kept secret books.
We may be able to round up
the whole gang if we can locate them.
I entrust the matter to you.
Yes, sir.
On that note...
I heard Simon Ulster passed.
My condolences. When is the funeral?
Today. Only for close family.
Will you be going alone?
Yes. Why?
I can't say much has changed on our end.
Second Prince Roderick is still
avoiding public appearances.
SECOND PRINCE OF FARIS
RODERICK
Third Princess Alexandra
is still locked in the tower
THIRD PRINCESS OF FARIS
ALEXANDRA
and on track to be burned.
And Fourth Prince Theophilis
is already acting like he's king.
FOURTH PRINCE OF FARIS
THEOPHILIS
I hear his followers have even
picked a date for the coronation.
Then the one behind
the Holy Grail of Eris must be...
Indeed, Fourth Prince Theophilis
seems the obvious suspect.
Why, Connie!
Mylene.
Who are these ladies?
We were just leaving.
Mylene, how is your work?
I'm writing articles to sell to the papers
on my way to becoming a real reporter.
My latest is on the suspicious death
of Edmond Park.
Who's Edmond Park?
The head of an accounting firm.
He was found murdered.
It appears to have been
a work-related vendetta.
His clients included the Raven Trading
Company and Saint Nicholas Hospital.
Did she say Saint Nicholas Hospital?
Say, Mylene, isn't Saint Nicholas
the hospital Earl Campbell used to run?
I see you know all about it!
Just between us, I hear Edmond Park
and Earl Campbell were gambling buddies.
And it seems one gambling den
in particular was his favorite.
It's under a restaurant called
The Goat's Hoof.
What are you waiting for?
How did I get myself into this?
What are you doing in a place like this?
Dear me. It's Kimberly Smith
of the Violet Association.
She's not wearing pink?!
Your order?
Meat on the bone.
The kind where top and bottom
add up to seven.
So that's what you're here for.
Sorry, downstairs isn't open yet.
Oh, what a shame.
But I'm only here to pick up
something for Ed today.
This way.
I assume you're here
about the Edmond Park case.
Who told you?
A friend. She wants to be a reporter.
My. She has promise.
Aren't you engaged to Randolph Ulster?
Do you know who the Ulsters are?
"Ulster" isn't merely a surname.
It's also a title for agents who
dispose of the royal family's enemies.
Agents?
Randolph serves in the military now,
but the late Simon Ulster trained him,
even though the duty
has long since become a formality.
E-Excuse me, but why tell me this?
Good question. I also—
Here.
This is it. Some kind of secret
accounting ledger, I hear.
Why, thank you.
Aren't those people...
They really must not want us
reading that secret ledger.
Keep your eyes on me.
Put it in your purse.
This is all the help I can give you.
Go out the back door. Hurry now.
But what about you?
I don't need deadweight.
I was trained by Simon Ulster as well.
He should be at Simon's funeral now.
Take good care of Junior.
That's not what you should be doing.
Right.
Miss Grail?
I saw it was raining.
What brings you here?
Well, the thing is,
Kimberly left this in my care.
How many times must I tell you
not to act on your own?
I-I'm sorry.
But Your Lordship was alone too.
So won't you call us even for today?
Don't I unnerve you?
Pardon?
My parents, my brother,
Lily, my granduncle...
People close to me keep dying.
Don't you think I really am
like Death himself?
Your fiancée...
lost her last betrothed to another woman,
made a spectacle of herself at a ball,
gets mixed up in one criminal
incident after another,
and, worst of all, she's haunted
by the wickedest woman of the age.
Doesn't that unnerve you?
Let's leave together, Your Lordship.
Yes.
THE HOLY GRAIL OF ERIS
Translation:
William Varteresian
Subtitle Timing:
Edgar Cruz
Subtitle Editing:
Riley Dalton
Quality Check:
SMR
Translation Check:
Sriram Gurunathan